<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sp3ppr</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sp3ppr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;CC-BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Open Source Software</title>
      <link>/posts/opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/opensource/</guid>
      <description>Open-Source and the free software community has flourished in the recent years with developments and collaborative projects from multi-million dollar corporations to individual ninja devs across the globe many systems across the globe rely on opensource software and their maintainers.
From servers running the linux kernel to sending encrypted emails with confidential data,opensource libraries and projects have made the software world flourish with projects like flutter,to the code editor I&amp;rsquo;m using to write this blog Vscode,the framework that is used to serve this website Hugo,to the shell that I run on my computer oh-my-fish are made possible by countless opensource software contributors on platforms like Github,Gitlab and Bitbucket that have made this dream come true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encoding,Encryption and Hashing</title>
      <link>/posts/encoding_encryption_hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/encoding_encryption_hashing/</guid>
      <description>Encoding, Encryption, and Hashing are terms that are often confused with each other.
Securing things is important and you need tools and technologies to secure products.
Encoding,Encryption and hashing are techniques to convert the format of data and play a important role in the infosec world in terms of securing data.
There is often significant confusion around the differences between encryption, encoding, hashing,
ENCODING Encoding is to transform data so that it can be properly (and safely) be consumed by a different type of system,whether it be sending binary data over email, or viewing special characters on a web page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-Source Intelligence and Digital Foot printing</title>
      <link>/posts/osint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/osint/</guid>
      <description>Malicious actors have been using specially crafted tools to collect information (like the police have search tools across a number of databases) and data companies collect so much information about us that a lot of free tools (OSINT) can be used to collect that information.
 So, what does an innocent individual have in their arsenal to defend himself? Knowing what information is out there using OSINT tools.
Digital Footprint</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Your Digital Self</title>
      <link>/posts/protecting_your_digital_self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/protecting_your_digital_self/</guid>
      <description>This simple advice will help to protect you against hackers and government surveillance.
The internet today is filled with news of breached and compromised accounts on various platforms and how the governments are able to surveil there own citizens.
The question now is Whether the government is the good guy or the bad guy and I certainly have had a hard time figuring it out.
Well if you are like, “I got nothing to hide” then you should probably reconsider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi. #!/usr/bin/env bash echo &amp;#34;sp3ppr&amp;#34; University = SRM Institute of Science and Technology I&amp;rsquo;m Shagun, and I go by sp3ppr on the Internet. I&amp;rsquo;m a Compsci student. My primary interest is information security and love contributing to opensource projects. I have great interest in GNU/Linux. After a long time of distro-hopping, I now settle with Arch Linux.
The existence of this blog The most important characteristic of people is their ability to think.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>